### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Name: Jantsje Maria Mol, MSc.

Date of birth: 17-08-1990

Address: NU-8A40, De Boelelaan 1111, 1081 HV Amsterdam

E-mail: j.m.mol@vu.nl
Website: www.jantsje.nl



Jantsje Mol is a PhD candidate in the department of Environmental Economics of IVM Institute for Environmental Studies at the VU University Amsterdam. She has a research master in Neuroeconomics from Maastricht University, with a particular focus on experimental economics and behavioral economics. Her MSc thesis examined the possibilities of virtual reality (VR) as a new tool in experimental economics.

Currently, Jantsje is working on the PhD project concerning individual flood-preparedness for Low-Probability/High-Impact (LPHI) flood risk. This project aims at improving individual flood-preparedness by finding the determinants of individual decisions to invest in flood damage mitigation measures. She designs and conducts economic lab and field experiments to study how mitigation decisions are related to insurance incentives. Her main interests are behavioral economics and experimental economics.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., and De Moel, H. (2020). Insights into flood risk misperceptions of homeowners in the Dutch river delta. Accepted at Risk Analysis.
- Mol, J.M., van der Heijden, E.C.M., Potters, J.J.M., (2020). (Not) alone in the world: Cheating in the presence of a virtual observer. *Experimental Economics*. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10683-020-09644-0
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., and Blasch, J. E. (2020). Risk reduction in compulsory disaster insurance: Experimental evidence on moral hazard and financial incentives. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 84 (February 2020), 101500 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.101500
- Mol, J.M., (2019). Goggles in the lab: Economic experiments in immersive virtual environments. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 79(C), 155-164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.02.007
- Mol, J.M., Botzen, W.J.W., Blasch, J.E., (2018). Behavioral motivations for self-insurance under different disaster risk insurance schemes. *Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization*, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2018.12.007

## **EDUCATION**

2016 – present PhD candidate in behavioral economics of natural disaster risk

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Institute for Environmental Studies, department of Environmental Economics

Research visit Risk Management and Decision Processes Center, Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania

2014 – 2016 Master of Science in Cognitive & Clinical Neuroscience (Research Master)

Maastricht University Track: Neuroeconomics.

Internship: Economic Experiments in Virtual Reality, Tilburg University, grade 9/10

**2011 – 2014 Bachelor of Science** 

**Tilburg University** 

Liberal Arts & Sciences. Major: Social Sciences. Graduated cum laude. Semester abroad at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

## SEMINAR AND CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

2020 - 5<sup>th</sup> Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Heidelberg (poster)

2019 - Norms and Behavioral Change Workshop, University of Pennsylvania (poster)

- BEEMA5, Villanova

- SPUDM, Amsterdam (poster) Runner up Best Poster Award
- WINK Nudging and Beyond, Utrecht University
- European conference on risk perception, Université de Cergy Pontoise, Paris (invited)

This version: March 2020. Download latest version from: <a href="https://www.jantsje.nl/files/CV.pdf">https://www.jantsje.nl/files/CV.pdf</a>

2018 - CEAR/MRIC Behavioral Insurance Workshop, Munich

ESA World Meeting, Berlin

- 3<sup>rd</sup> Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Hamburg

BEEC, Universidad del Rosario, Bogotá (poster)

2017 - VR for experimental economics workshop, RWTH Aachen (invited)

TIBER Symposium, Tilburg University

- CREED lunch seminar, University of Amsterdam

2016 - GSS Seminar, Tilburg University

- Scientific Talk at RM Graduation, Maastricht University

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

**Teaching Assistant** 

2016 – present Environmental Economics (Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam
2018 – present Statistics in R (practical, Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Theses supervision

2019 A. Carvallo, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, MSc.
 2018 A. Molenaar, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, BSc.

Lecturer

Dec 2019 Guest lecture on Experimental Economics, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*Mar 2018 oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*Nov 2017 oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, *Tilburg University* 

### **SKILLS**

**Languages**: Dutch: native

English: fluent

German, Spanish, French: basic

Software skills: R, Stata, SPSS, Microsoft Office, oTree, Adobe Creative Suite: advanced

MATLAB, HTML, Django, Python, JavaScript, ArcGIS Pro: intermediate